### VIDAL QUINI, NICOLÁS EMANUEL

#### **Geographer - Phd in Geography**

Age: 30 @ nicolasvidalquini@gmail.com

Noble around 33 Condo Soi Sukhunvit 33, 17/107, Bangkok, Thailand

in https://www.linkedin.com/in/nicolas-vidal-quini-/

 $\begin{tabular}{ll} \$ & \textbf{https://www.researchgate.net/profile/Nicolas-Emanuel-Vidal-Quini} \end{tabular}$ 

ORCID 0000-0003-4352-6734





### **SUMMARY**

Geographer with a focus on remote sensing, GIS, and environmental modeling, specializing in medium-resolution optical and SAR images. Over the past 6 years, I dedicated myself to my doctoral thesis work, emphasizing expertise in assessing environmental risks and Wetlands. Possessing exceptional communication and teamwork skills, I am actively contributing to the Laboratory of Geotechnologies at the Department of Geography and Tourism, National University of South, and the Argentine Institute of Oceanography, applying my comprehensive knowledge in these domains.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### **Doctoral Fellow**

Instituto Argentino de Oceanografía. CONICET

# April 2018 - March 2024

Scope: Explored and assessed environmental risks in fluvial systems and wetlands using optical and radar satellite imagery contributing valuable insights for preserving critical ecosystems in the Buenos Aires region.

#### Researcher in Geotechnology Laboratory

Departamento de Geografía y Turismo - Universidad Nacional del sur https://labgeot.uns.edu.ar/

**♀** 2017 - March 2024

Scope: Organize geographic information in an interoperable and high-quality manner, facilitating the efficient management and planning of geographic space. Committed to optimizing resource utilization in alignment with the goals of sustainable development within the framework of the 2030 SDGs.

Tools: Geospatial Information - Water source - Land use- Land cover.

Scope: Development of training courses and training in using different geotechnologies programs.

Tools: Geospatial Information - Remote Sensing - Geography Informations Systems and Science - Google Earth Engine.

Scope: Field spectral signature measurement for land cover and use maps.

Tools: Radiometer spectrum Ocean Optics, Weather Station, GPS.

### **MOTIVATION**

Dedicated to team growth and development, actively sharing knowledge to strengthen the team. Passionate about introducing innovative ideas and technologies, particularly in environmental modeling. Committed to staying at the forefront, innovating, and applying future technologies to address challenges in a sustainable world.

### **SKILLS**

R Packages Google Earth Engine Phyton basic SQL basic Java Scripts QGIS ArcGIS **SNAP** Geoserver Geospatial data analyst Machine learning images Technical report Scientific article Optical and SAR images Geography Analyst Wetlands Risk Analyst Environmental Risk Analyst Spatial data infrastructure oral presentations SWOT matrix communication skills

### **LANGUAGES**

Spanish: Native

English: Upper Intermediate (B2)

## DEGREES AND CERTIFICATIONS

Phd in Geography.

Instituto Argentino de Oceanografía (Argentina).

**#** 2018 - 2024

Bachelor in Geography (5 years degree).

Universidad Nacional del Sur (Argentina).

**#** 2012 - 2018

Research within the framework of the Spatial Data Infrastructure of the Southwest of Buenos Aires Working Group (IDESoB).

Departamento de Geografía y Turismo - Universidad Nacional del sur

**♀** Jun 2019 - March 2024

Scope: Normalization of vector and raster data for the Southwest of Buenos Aires province according to the Argentinian Infrastructure Spatial Data

Tools: Geonetwork - ISO standards.

Participate in the wetland inventory for the Buenos Aires Province. Ministry of Environment of the Buenos Aires Province.

₩ 2023

Scope: Multi-scalar landscape analysis. Methodological adjustments for the Province of Buenos Aires.

Tools: Geospatial Tools and Geographic Information.

Production of crop maps and recording of spectral signatures for the National Institute of Agricultural Technology.

**#** 2019 - 2022

Scope: Land use and change maps and, elaboration of crop spectral signatures.

Tools: Radiometer spectrum Ocean Optics - Satellite image.

#### **Professional Training**

₩ 2022

Scope: Professional training with students and teachers from Agrarian Secondary Education School No. 1 in Bajo Hondo, Province of Buenos Aires. Geotechnologies and their agricultural applications.

Tools: Radiometer spectrum Ocean Optics - Satellite image.

#### Participation in Research Projects

March 2016 - April 2023

Project Member: "Application of geographic information technologies to the comprehensive and comparative study of environmental problems".

Tools: Geospatial Information - Remote Sensing - Geography Informations Systems and Science.

Project Member: "Open system of a georeferenced data bank for educational purposes and links to the labor market".

Tools: Geospatial Information.

# PUBLICATION IN PEER-REVIEWED JOURNALS

### Publication in peer-reviewed international journals

**2018 - 2024** 

Paper: Vidal Quini, N. E., Lucía M. Laffeuillade, and Geraldi, A. M. (2024). Environmental characterization of pampean wetlands through multi-temporal analysis sentinel 1. Journal: Geografía y Sistemas de Información Geográfica (GEOSIG).

Paper: Vidal Quini, N. E., and Geraldi, A. M. (2023). Methodology for the analysis of the frequency of shallow water bodies in the Pampean region, Argentina. Journal: Investigaciones Geográficas. https://doi.org/10.14198/INGEO.23410.

Paper: Vidal Quini, N. E., and Geraldi, A. M. (2021). Synergy of Sentinel 1 and Sentinel 2 A images for the delimitation of wetlands from an ecohydrogeomorphic approach. Journal: Cuadernos Geográficos-ISSN: 2340-0129. Editorial de la Universidad de Granada. DOI: 10.30827/cuadgeo.v60i3.18039

### Publication in peer-reviewed National journals

**2018 - 2024** 

Short Paper: Vidal Quini, N. E., and Geraldi, A. M. (2021). Sentinel-1 SAR classification and water stress index using Landsat 8 for the characterization and identification of wetlands and associated ecosystems. Journal: Libro de resúmenes XIX Reunión de Trabajo en Procesamiento de la Información y Control (RPIC'2021).

Paper: Vidal Quini N. and Geraldi A. M. (2022). "Contribution of remote sensing for the study of environmental vulnerability of wetlands in southwestern Buenos Aires province". Journal: Contribuciones Científicas GÆA 34, 52-62 – ISSN: 0328-3194 (en línea). Editorial GÆA Sociedad Argentina de Estudios Geográficos.

Paper: Laffeuillade L., Vidal Quini N., Peñas V.H and Geraldi A. M.(2022). "ASPO effect (Preventive and Mandatory Social Isolation) in the atmosphere of the southwest of the province of Buenos Aires, Argentine Republic". Journal: Estudios socioterritoriales – ISSN: 1853-4392 (en línea). Editorial Centro de Investigaciones Geográficas CIG - Instituto de Geografía, Historia y Ciencias Sociales IGEHCS. Facultad de Ciencias Humanas UNCPBA/CONICET.

### Conferences, Congresses and oral presentations 2016 – 2023

Scope: Participation and oral presentations in 15 international and national conferences and symposiums.

# EDUCATION AND TRAINING COURSES

Phd. in Geography. Application of optical images and Radar to the space-time analysis of the anthropogenic incidence and climatic variability in the Arroyo Corto, Pescado y Cura Malal basins and the wetlands of Laguna Alsina

Universidad Nacional del Sur.

## 2018 - Present

Postgraduate program

Universidad Nacional del Sur.

## 2018 - Present

Over 300 hours in postgraduate courses focused on Geography, Remote Sensing, GIS, and Data Analysis and Modeling

### **MISCELLANUEOS DATA**

Date and Place of Birth: November 18, 1993, Viedma Río Negro,

Argentina Status: Single Citizen: Argentina

Dedicated to charity work in a Community Kitchen in Bahía Blanca, Argentina. 2018-2023. Organizing team activities and events